### Abel Ghebrezadik

Senior Software Engineer

Address: Enfield, EN3 | Phone: 07527841324 | Email: abel\_g@hotmail.co.uk

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/abel-ghebrezadik | Website: https://www.abelghebz.com

### **Profile**

A mathematics graduate, I am inquisitive, analytical, and numerical by nature. I approach everyday problems in a logical, clear, calculated process. Earlier experience, as a team leader, role in hospitality and teaching helped develop my communication and leadership skills. Initiative-taking, resilient, and fearless attitude, I resigned from a role in financial services to learn how to code, as I needed a more stimulating and challenging role. I have 8 years of commercial experience and counting.

# **Technical Skills**

Languages & Frameworks: C# .NET Core/Framework, SQL (MSSQL, MySQL), Vue.js, React.js, Node.js, WinForms, WPF

Tools & Technologies: AWS, Microservices Architecture, REST APIs, Unit Testing, CI/CD, Agile Methodologies

Recreational Programming: C++, Python, Java

# **Work Experience**

Fvtvre | .NET 8 microservice platform, B2B property management product

Senior Software Engineer (April 2024 – July 2024)

- Developed a .NET 8 microservice API and frontend for property management.

## SalaryFinance | .NET 6 microservices platform. B2B2C loan products and salary advancement

Senior Software Engineer (July 2022 - April 2024) | Software Engineer (August 2021 - June 2022)

- Technical lead on critical project that saved the company millions in fines. 70/80 hours p/w for in October 2023. 50/70 hours for 3 months between September December 2023.
- Resolved 500+ production issues in 6-months, creation date as far back as Sept 2021, 5x more than any other engineer, a company OKR, improved team efficiency and OLAs unblocking new feature development.
- Built new front-end features and back-end services features for customer ops to reduce raised production issues
- Proactively applying root cause fixes to recurring issues in key microservices.
- Created and updated processes and playbooks to aid knowledge sharing.
- Mentored Junior Engineers and took on Lead Developer duties in the Lead's absence.

## **Optal** | .NET Framework monolith platform. B2B e-card payments for travel websites

Senior Software Engineer (July 2020 - April 2021) | Software Engineer (May 2018 - June 2020)

- Developed WinForms/WPF desktop applications for accounts management system which reconciled, monitored, and settled.
- Monitored millions of daily transactions from travel websites Expedia and Booking.com reconciled with Ixaris and MasterCard data.
- Settled transactions across 50+ bank accounts in multiple currencies across 10 international Optal entities.

# FDM Group | Graduate Scheme. Contracted to London Metal Exchange

IT Consultant (Junior Software Engineer) (May 2016 – May 2018)

- Created a SOAP API for internal staff to retrieve company data.
- Scripted in variety of languages from Perl, PowerShell, Batch in archaic systems.
- Developed MIFID II regulatory reporting APIs, ensuring compliance with standards.

#### **Education**

University of Southampton | BSc Mathematics - 2:1 (2009 – 2013)

Woodhouse College | A-Levels: Mathematics (A), Economics (A), Sociology (B) (2007 - 2009)

## **Interests**

In my spare time I create websites and applications, DJing and creating mixes. I have also been known to enjoy a challenge; Hackney Half, London Olympic triathlon, and Tough Mudder.